Miscellaneous Benjamin Franklin Collections 1710-1822 Mss.B.F85.misc
American Philosophical Society
- Benjamin Franklin Miscellaneous Collection, 1710-1793; Mss.B.F85.[numeral]; 531 items
  - Letter to Capt. [Timothy] Folger, 1770 April 14; ALS, 1p.and end. Enc. wanting.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Encloses map of the island of St. John's and business of the island.
  - Letter to [Deborah] Franklin, 1770 April 20; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Introduces Miss Farquarson and Miss Smith who go to Philadelphia to ply their trades of milliner and mantuamaker.
    From original in possession of the Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, Utica, N.Y.
  - Agreement to Form the Ohio Company, 1770 May 7; Photo.of A.D.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (from catalogue of Robert F. Batchelder, Ambler, Pa.)
  - Letter to David Hall, Philadelphia, 1770 June 11; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Wishes to be in Philadelphia before final settlement of partnership is done.
  - Letter to S[amuel] Franklin, 1770 June 8; Photostat of copy of L. Portion of p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From copy in New England Historic Genealogical Society. On same sheet with letter of July 17, 1767.
    Printed: Smyth, v.5,263.
  - to Mary [Hewson Stevenson], 1770 July 18; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Mary Stevenson had married William Hewson
  - Letter to Lord Le Despencer, 1770 July 26; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Entreats him to urge the plan of reconciliation between the two countries. Enclosed letter from Col. Bouquet shows Franklin's influence in America for his Majesty's service. Plea for continuance in his present office.
    Presented by Lessing J. Rosenweld, May 1953.
  - Letter to N.W. Jones, 1770 July 6; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Sends mace and gowns ordered [for Georgia Assembly ?].
    APS has Jones's reply of Oct.9, 1770 acknowledging above.
  - Letter to N. W. Jones, 1770 October 10; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Amount of bill for gowns and mace. Duty of American agents.
  - Letter to Dear Sister [Jane Mecom], 1770 November 7,9; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Hopes to return early in summer. Death of Mr. Whitefield. Arrival of Kinsmen [Jonathan, jr., and Josiah Williams]. Advises her not to be concerned about any abuses he receives in the English press.
    Printed: Van Doren's Franklin-Mecom, pp.117-118.
  - Letter to Deborah Franklin, ca. 1770; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Acknowledges her letter of October 14 [1770 - in APS].
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, 1771 Mar. 30; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Deborah Read Rogers, 1708-1774
    News of family and friends, especially of Benny Bache.
  - Letter to Humphry Marshall, 1771 April 22; L. Facsimile.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Facsimile made by Thomas Fisher, Philad., (n.d.). For other facsimiles of another edition. see: F.P.,v.69,no.1: and B: F85Le. copy 2. 14x8-1/2.
  - Letter to [Humphrey Marshall], 1771 April 22; TL Cy, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Letter to M. Le Roy, 1771 May 17; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Introduces Mr. Smith, a young American. Sir John Pringle and he frequently recollect their visits with M. Le Roy in Paris.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin; Ephrata, 1771 June 12; ALS, 3p. Bound volume.; Miller, Peter, 1710-1796
    This is followed by an introduction(pp.1-4); an elaboration of Conrad Beissel's Dissertations on Mans Fall (printed in Ephrata 1765) (pp.4-117);Supplement to the antecedent (pp.119-127); translation of Beissel's Ninety nine mystical sentences (pub. by B. Franklin, 1730) (pp.127-136); Appendix to the foregoing sentences, containing a collection of apopthegms taken from the Father's writings (pp.137-147).
    Inscription - inside front cover: These letters and manuscript belong to Doctor Benjamin Franklin of Pensylvania who gave them to me - probably in the hand of Jonathan Shipley, the Bishop of St. Asaph.
    Printed: Sachse, J.F. A unique manuscript by Rev. Peter Miller... Lancaster, 1912. Also in: Journal of the Lancaster Country Historical Soc. v.61, no.1,p.18.
    See Franklin's letter to Deborah Franklin, Jan 28, 1772 (APS collection, and Smyth 5, 372)
  - Letter to Samuel Franklin, 1771 July 12; Photostat of copy of L. Portion of 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.5,333.
  - Letter to [Charles Willson] Peale, 1771 July 4; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Compliments him on the success of his business in his native country. "The arts have always travelled Westward, and there is no doubt of their flourishing hereafter on our side the Atlantic..."
    Reproduced: APS Library Bulletin for 1946, p.15.
    Printed: C. Sellers' "The Peale portraits of Benjamin Franklin in APS Library Bulletin for 1950-p.252.
    Printed: The Crayon, vol. l,p.81-83,Feb. 7, 1855.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklyn (sic), 1771 July 20; ALS, 1p.; Cushing, Thomas, 1725-1788
    At the desire of the House of Representatives sends copy of commissioners' taxes in various towns.
  - Letter to William Strahan; Edinburg, 1771 November 17; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.5, 344.
  - Letter to [Benjamin] Frankland;Edinburgh, 1771 November 19; Photocopy of A.L. 3p.; Drummond, Agatha, Lady Kames, 1711-95
    To send portrait of Penn to Franklin. Mentions Marchant.
    [From original in the His. soc. of PA.]
  - Letter to [Mary] Hewson; Preston, 1771 November 25; ALS, 2p. Contains a P.S. to Dorothea Blunt.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth 5, 345.
  - Letter to Smith, Wright and Gray, 1771 December 10; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Order to pay Josiah Williams 10 guineas.
  - Order to Messrs. Smith, Wright and Gray, to pay Mr. Zumpe 18 guineas, 1771 December 16; A.N.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    [Mr. Zumpe is probably Johann Zumpe, a celebrated maker of small pianos in London during this period]
  - Forms of notes, used in the publick Library at Philadelphia, 177[1]; 1p.; Library Company of Philadelphia.
    Ms. D. in handwriting of Benjamin Franklin.
    Found originally in Library Co. Charter, laws...Phila., 1770: 027:L62ch
  - Letter to Jonathan Williams, jr., Boston, 1772 January 12; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Settlement of accounts with Mr. Warren.
  - Letter to Jona[than] Williams [sr.], 1772 January 13; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    has just returned from a journey through Ireland and Scotland; personal financial matters.
    Purchased at Morley sale, May 29, 1942; cannot find in print.
  - Letter to Revd. [Richard] Price, 1772 February 11; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    A.P.S. has draft: F.P.45,54.
    Printed: Smyth, 5,389.
  - Resolutions.., 1772 February 2, 5; Photostat, 2p.; U.S. Commissioners to France
    Concerning the attitude of the U.S. towards France or Spain, In case either of these nations should conclude a Treaty of Amity and Commerce with the U.S., and in consequence enter into a war with Great Britain. Also a resolve to defend the support the public cause at all hazards...risk their liberty or life (Hays Cal., v. 4,475).
    With this is what appears to be a preliminary draft of the Feb. 2nd document - Photostat, 1p.
    From original in University of Pennsylvania.
  - Letter to Dr. Thomas Bond, 1772 February 5; ALS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.5,384. Mentions books, etc. presented to A.P.S. by various persons.
  - Letter to [John] Morgan, 1772 February 5; Enlargement print of ALS, 1p., end.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Is"pleased to see their college begin to make some figure as a school of physic."
  - Letter to Humphrey Marshall, 1772 March 20; T.C. of L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Presented by Ed. Bury, Jan. 1947.
    Printed: Darlington, Memorials of J. Bartram and H. Marshall, p.518.
  - Letter to My dear Child [Deborah Franklin], 1772 June 2; ANS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Is well; promises to write fully by Osborn.
  - to Mary [Hewson], Birmingham, 1772 July 8; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    (Printed: Sparks, p.148; Stifler, p.131- neither print a short note in the original)
  - Letter to Erasmus Darwin, 1772 August 1; Photocopy, 4p. end. 12-3/4x8.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Discusses his alphabet. Difficulty of pronunciation. Talks of his bad health. Mr. Walsh's experiments on the torpedo fish. Letters being sent.
  - [Document in re stroke of torpedo (fish) being electrical] London, 1772 August 12; A.D.S. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    End: Franklin's instructions to try if the stroke of the Torpedo be electrical.
  - Letterbook, 1772 August 22; Drafts of 11 ALS,'s [3 leaves]; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Contains letters addressed to: Messrs.Towers and Leacock, the Library Co., Mr. Tyler, Sam. Rhoads, Dr. Evans,John Bartram,Dr. Smith, Messrs. Reynell, Rhoads and Pemberton, Anth Benezet,Dr. Rush, and Rev. Mr. Coombe.
  - Letter to Dr.[William] Smith, 1772 August 22; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    For draft of same letter see in his Letter book for same date.
    Printed: Smyth, v.5,431.
  - Letter to [William] Hunter, 1772 October 30; Photostat, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Relative to disagreement between Dr. Hunter and Mr. Hewson.
    (from original in the Royal College of Surgeons of England: presented by William R. LeFanu, librarian, November 1952)
  - Letter to "My dear Child" [Deborah Franklin], 1772 October 7; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Franked: B Free Franklin.
    Is well except for several recent touches of the gout. Sends remembrances from English friends to her and Sally. Sends love to"Benny boy."
  - Letter to the Royal Academy of Sciences, Paris, 1772 November 16; Photocopy, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Acknowledges election to membership.
    (From the Hotel Drouot Salle No. 8, le mercredi 20 fevrier 1974 a 14 heures 30 precises.)
  - Letter to unidentified recipient, 1772 November 26; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Recommends Sir John Pringle for the presidency of the Royal Society.
  - Musical expression; [passions and sentiments] capable of expression by musick, ca. 1772; A.D. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Along side the terms in Franklin's hand are corresponding words in French and notation in handwriting of the Abbé Morellet.
    Reproduced in LB 1955,378.
  - Letter to [Edward] Bancroft, [London]; Craven St, 1773 May 21; Photocopy, 1p.add.end.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Congratulations on Bancroft's election to Royal Soc.
  - Letter to S[amuel] F[ranklin], 1773 July 7; Photostat of copy of L. Portion of p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From copy in New England Historic Genealogical Society. On same sheet with letter of July 17,1767.
    Printed: Smyth, v.6, 95.
  - Letter to "My dear child" [Deborah Franklin], 1773 July 7; LS Cy, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Presented by Mr. Dayton Kohler, March 1954.
    Printed: Smyth 6, 73, under the date of July 6, 1773. FAcsimile in Smith, Historical curiosites, 973.3:Sm6en.46
  - Letter to Samuel Franklin, 1773 July 7; Photocopy, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Friendly letter, holding promise of wellbeing, due to the "constant Growth of the Country."
    From original in possession of Mrs. J. H. Bradshaw, Lahaska, Penna.; Jan. 1976.
  - Letter to Lord Le Despencer, 1773 November 24; Photocopy, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Concerning an estate in Canada and cites Maseres' opinion of it.
    From copy in possession of Sir Francis Dashwood, bart. West Wycombe Park, Bucks.
  - Letter to [Deborah Franklin], 1774 February 20; Typed extract of L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Note that he has written more fully by other ships.
  - Letter to [Sir Francis Dashwood, baron Le Despencer], 1774 April 14; Photocopy, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Concerning carving below sculptured work.
    From original in possession of Sir Francis Dashwood, bt., West Wycombe Park, High Wycombe, Bucks.
  - Letter to [Deborah Franklin], 1774 May 7; Fragment of A.L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    In Jared Sparks' hand. See letter in Franklin Papers, May 5, 1774 - Vol.46(2) 90.
  - Letter to [David] Williams, Chelsea, 1774 May 9; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    "Presented to Mr. Franklin W. Smith... [signed] Joseph Evans, 1878. Neither Mrs. Stevenson, Mrs. Hewson, nor he can visit as invited. Sends their regrets.
  - Letter to Samuel Rhoads, Philadelphia, 1774 June 30; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Forwards pamphlets for distribution among the committee.
  - Letter to [Benjamin] Rush, 1774 July 25; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Smyth, v.6,236. Mentions books, etc. presented to A.P.S. by various persons and institutions.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, 1775 Feb. 20; ALS, 2p.; Howe, Richard Howe, Earl, 1726-1799
    Lord Hyde is of the opinion that Franklin's principles and Parliament's concerning the American contest are so far apart that a meeting to discuss them would only give Dr. Franklin unnecessary trouble.
    For Dr. Franklin's reply, see his letter of same date.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, 1775 Nov. 30; A.L. 3d person, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Accompanied by note by E.D. Gillespie
    Concerning ground rent.
  - Letter to Lord Howe, 1775 February 20; ADr, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Having nothing further to offer on the American business will not visit Lord Hyde.
    (see Lord Howe to BF of same date, to which this apparently is a reply)
  - Letter to Humphry Marshall, 1775 March 13; TL Cy 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Printed: Darlington, Memorials of J. Bartram and H. Marshall, 1849, p.521.
  - Letter to Joseph Galloway, 1775 May 8; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Concerned at Galloway's resolution to quit public life. Proposed visit. Mentions William Franklin. Presented by Mrs. Arthur Loeb, Jan.1995.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, 1775 May 14; Photostat, 3p.; Mecom, Jane Franklin, 1712-1794
    Franklin's safe arrival in America. Evacuation of Boston. Is with Mr. and Mrs. Greene. News of family and friends.
    Contains also a letter from Caty Greene to [Dr. Franklin]; [apparently same date]
    From original in Yale university.
    Printed: Roelker's Franklin-Greene Correspondence, p.50;Van Doren, Franklin-Mecom,pp.153-156.
  - Letter to [William] Strahan, 1775 July 5; Facsimile of ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Facsimiles of this letter are found also in:
    B. Franklin. Memoirs of the life and writings...ed. by W.T. Franklin. v.2, London,1818 - facing p.1.
    ---- Memoirs of the life and writings... v.1, Philadelphia, Duane, 1818 - between pp.356 and 357.
    ---- Correspondence inedite et secrète...
    v.2, Paris, 1817. Frontispiece.
    Reproduced: APS Library Bulletin for 1845 - fig.17
    Facsimile also in: Gloason's pictorial drawing-room companion, see Collection of Broadsides no.134
    Also printed in: Pamphlets on Franklinina no 62; Austen-Leigh, R.A. The story of a printing house, p.21
    Printed: Smyth,V.6,407;N.J.hist.soc.Proc.n.s.v.11,no.2,p.282.
  - Letter to [William] Strahan, 1775 July 5; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From original in Library of Congress;contains also photostat of facsimile of letter in same collection.
  - Letter to Nicholas Cook[e]; Watertown, 1775 August 14; LS, 2p.; Massachusetts Colony. General court
    Pertaining to the interception of mail by a man of war at Conanicut ferry and requesting a change in the route.
    Purchased at the sale of John Gribbel's library, October 31, 1940; of. Parke-Bernet catalogue, no.223, item 253.
    Printed: American Antiquarian Society, Proceedings, n.s. v.36,1927, p.266.
  - Letter to B. Franklin, 1775 August 15; ALS, 1p.; Cooke, Nicholas, 1717-1782
    informs him of the interception of the post rider by a ship of war at the ferry to Newport; recommends a different route.
    Printed: American Antiquarian Society, Proceedings, n.s. v.36,1927, p.266-267.
  - Recommendation to the Associators to make use of pikes, 1775 August 26; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    In connection with this document see article by William A. Hunter, "Two 'new' Franklin manuscripts,".
    Photostat presented by Mr. Hunter, 1953.
    Printed: Colonial Records, v.10,322 - Minutes of the Council of Safety.
  - Letter to [Nicholas] Cooke, 1775 August 27; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    acknowledges letter of August 15 re the loss of the mail and suggests that he "take the advice... of the principal people in your government."
  - [Power of attorney to Benjamin Franklin; particularly with respect to wages due him as wagon master during the Braddock campaign], 1775 Oct. 8; Pr.DS, 1p.; Read, John
    With this are: E. Braddock to [John] Read; May 21,1755 - appointment as waggonmaster. (B:F85.x7b)
    Certification by Thos. Scott that wages are due John Read, waggon master; Oct. 1, 1755. (B:F85.x7c)
    Labaree, Papers, VI, 221-222.
  - Letter to Jos. Greenleaf; Cambridge, 1775 October 26; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Postal affairs. Presented by Mr. Samuel H. McVitty, March 1955.
    Facsimile.
  - Commission to George Taylor, to serve as Colonel, 1st battalion of Pennsylvania Associators, Northampton Co, [1775]; Pr.DS; Committee of safety. Pennsylvania
    For account of printing of this form cf. Col. Rec.. 10,295.
  - Letter to Charles Lee, 1776 February 11; Photostat, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    TL Cy
    From original in possession of Justin G. Turner presented by Mr. Turner, Sept. 1953.
    Printed: Smyth 6, 438.
  - Letter to Jonathan Williams, 1776 March 29; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Personal letter.
    Paper contains interesting watermark.
  - Letter to [William] St[raha]n, 1776 March 29; Copy of L. 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    On his way to Canada. Breach between England and America grows wider. Barbarities on the part of the British.
  - Commission to Joseph Willson to serve as 1st Lieutenant of the armed boat, Congress: Phila, 1776 March 6; PrDS, 1p.; Pennsylvania. Committee of Safety
    Certification of induction on May 21, 1776 on reverse.
  - Instructions to privateers and vessels of war, 1776 April 3; D. 3p.; U.S. Congress
    Contains note by W.T.Franklin. In hand of Franklin's French secretary(?)
  - Letter to [John Philip] Schuyler; Montreal, 1776 May 1; Photocopy, 1p., enc. wanting; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Express appreciation for Schuyler's "Kind Attention" in aiding their journey. Mention John Carrol (sic).
    Presented by Robert B. Gillespie; January 1973.
  - Letter to William Bingham, 1776 June 3; LS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    orders of the Secret committee to procure arms for America. Purchased at the sale of John Gribbel's library, November 1, 1940; of Parke-Bernet catalogue, no.223, item 651.
  - Letter to Messrs. Richd. Harrison and Adrien Le Maitre, 1776 June 3; DS, 1p.; U.S. Continental congress. Committee of secret correspondence
    In hand of Robert Morris (?). On reverse is letter of same date to Le Maitre and Harrison, signed by B.Franklin, Benj. Harrison, Robt. Morris, John Dickinson, 1p. Instructions regarding cargo of Sloop Fanny.
    In connection with this document see another letter of same date from the Committee to William Bingham - B:F85 October
  - Letter to col. Bull, 1776 August 26; ALS, lp.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    The convention has granted his leave.
  - Letter to Col. [John] Bull, Perth Amboy, [1776] August 27.; Photo., 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    "B. Free Franklin" manuscript frank as continental Postmaster General.
    Presented by Richard C. Frajola,9/30/83. (See letter to W. Spawn, APS Archives.)
    For sale catalog (Frajola sale, 10 Sept. 1983) see card cat. for printed works.
  - Letter to W[illiam Temple] Franklin; Brunswick, 1776 Sept. 10; Photocopy D. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Concerns a letter and meeting with Lord Howe. Adams and Rutledge are with Franklin.
  - Commission to William Lowder to server as ensign of a Company of Foot in Col. Richard MCalister's batallion from York county, in the Flying Camp for the Middle States of America, 1776 Sept. 14; 1p.; Pennsylvania. Constitutional convention, 1776
    Printed D.S: B. Franklin, presid.
  - Letter to unidentified recipient-, 1776 October 1; LS.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Authorization to make application for all arms, ammunition, clothing, etc., that may arrive in Martinique for the U.S. Mentions M. Hortalez [Beaumarchais]
  - Receipt for payment of mortgage from Mary Pitts (or Pills), 1776 October 14; D.S. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Appears to have been cut from the records of William Parr, Recorder of Deeds
  - Letter to William Bingham, 1776 October 21; LS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Instructions relative to material which is to be shipped by M. Hortalez.
  - [Extracts of correspondence relating to loans to the U.S., by the U.S. Commissioners - Franklin, Deane, and Lee], 1777 January 14 - December 18; Photostat of D. 4p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    From original in the Library of Congress.
    Printed: Whanton, Dip. Cor.,v.2,p.250.
  - Letter to the Commissioners of the United States, 1777 June 30; D.S. 4p.; Williams, J
  - Letter to unidentified recipient, 1777 July 9; ALS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Notice from the Minister of Marine to give orders to armed vessels to depart the ports in 24 hours. Encloses instructions for Capt. Wilkes.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, 1777 Aug. 18; Photostat, 2p.; Mecom, Jane Franklin, 1712-1794
    Writes this for her son-in-law [Peter collas] recently exchanged for another prisoner of war. Death or Mrs. [William] Franklin.
    Original in Historical Society of Pennsylvania.
    Printed in Pennsylvania Magazine of History and Biography, v.72, no.3,p.265.
    Van Doren, Franklin-Mecom, pp.170-171.
  - Letter to Richard Peters, 1777 Sept. 12; Transcript of L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Transcript made by D.H. Wallace, March 1952.
    From original in Vail mss., Geneva, Switzerland, Miscellaneous.
    Printed: Smyth 7, 64.
  - to [Benjamin] Vaughan, 1777 Sept. 18; Photostat of A.L. 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Not printed in Smyth. Makes an appointment to meet Mr.Vaughan at "Les Bains de Poitevin" at six that evening.
  - Letter to Capt. John Folger; Passy near Paris, 1777 October 19; ALS, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Approval of his proposition to return in case of accident on coast.
  - Letter of marque to Stephen Marchant, 1777 October 8; Photostat, 2p.; U.S. Continental Congress
    with certification of authenticity by Stephen Marchant. Copy.
    (From original in public records office, London.)
    Presented by William Bell Clark.
  - Letter to [Due de La Rochefoucauld d'Enville ?], 1777 November 17; Photostat, 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Returns the Carolina constitution. News of the Amphitrite.
    From original in the Bibliothèque Municaple, Besancon, France, Collection J. Droz, T. 1.
  - Letter to captains of all ships of war and privateers on the rights of neutrals; Paris, 1777 November 21; DS, 3p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
  - Letter to [Jonathan] Williams [jr.], 1777 November 30; Photostat, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Pertains to Mr. Williams's accounts with M. Chaumont.
    Presented by Mr. Frederic R. Kirkland, April 1940.
    Cf. Parke-Bernet catalogue for sale on March 27-28, 1940, item no. 270 - sold for $160.
  - Letter to John Ross, Nantes; Paris, 1777 December 18; LS, 2p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Orders for a convoy. Requests money as soon as possible, due to their dire need.